本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
Rule the Court
I'm sure you're sick of hearing this,
but make sure your serves are strong.
耳にタコだろうがサブは強気で
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
向こうの１０番に多少決められるのは仕方ない
We can't do anything about
number ten scoring some points.
Force him to one side and then dig it out.
絞て拾おう
Yes, sir!
You guys are good.
お前達は強いよ
Yeah!
おしゃあ
とにかく及川のサブに好き勝手させないことを
Don't let Oikawa do whatever he wants with his serves!
I don't care how high you get the ball!
上でいいとにかく上げる
Just dig out his serves!
When you do, someone else will keep the rally going!
そうすりゃ誰かが繋ぐ
Yes, sir!
いつか倒さなければならない敵を宿敵と呼ぶのなら
If an enemy you must defeat
one day is called an archenemy,
then for us, Aoba Jousai is precisely that.
烏野にとての青葉城西がまさにそれ
The stage has been set.
戦いの舞台は整えました
宿敵との大一番勝つのは君達です
The victor in this battle against
our archenemy will be you guys!
Yessir!
In the final set,
ファイナルセト
we're going to surpass Aoba Jousai!
俺達は青葉城西を越えていく
このチムで越えていく
We'll surpass them with this team!
Karasuno, fight!
烏野ファイ
Yeah!
おおす
Episode Twenty-three:
"Team"
This is finally it.
いよいよだな
Yeah.
They'll finally settle things with Seijou in this set.
青城との決着をつけるセトだ
Give us a good serve!
ナイサ
旭行け
Go, Asahi!
All right!
しゃあ
Give us a good one, Oikawa!
及川さんナイサ
上げろなんとしても上に
Get it up.
You have to get the ball up no matter what.
最初で突き放されるわけにはいかない
We can't let them get ahead early.
We have to stop them here!
頼む一本で切てくれ
Olé!
It's so fast.
なんつスピド
It's going over the net! Watch for the return spike!
ネト越えるダイレクト来るぞ
I couldn't react even though he hit it right at me!
真正面なのに反応が遅れる
Just spike it, Kyoutani!
京谷ダイレクト
よしゃ
All right!
Good. Mad Dog's engine is still warm.
よし狂犬ちゃんのエンジンは暖またまま
やぱ厄介だな及川のサブ
Oikawa's serves are definitely a problem.
C'mon, you have to stop him.
頼む切てくれ
Keep fighting, guys!
烏野ファイト
Give us another good serve, Oikawa!
及川もう一本ナイサ
Olé!
おしゃあ
All right!
It's up!
上がた
Cover it!
Yeah!
しゃぁああ
Nice spike, Tanaka!
田中ナイスキ
They somehow managed to stop Oikawa.
なんとか切た
Thanks!
あざす
Well done, Ryuu!
龍よくやた
All right!
よしゃ
月島次サブ
Tsukishima! You're serving next!
Oh, right.
Aoba Jousai                  Karasuno
Give us a good serve, Tsukishima!
月島ナイサ
Got it!
オライ
狂犬ちゃん
Mad Dog!
よしゃ
Yeah!
いいぞいいぞ賢太郎押せ押せ賢太郎もう一本
ナイスキ
Nice spike!
Kyoutani has a lot more energy when he's in the front row.
やぱ京谷は前衛に上がてくると俄然元気だな
Hopefully he'll be able to keep it up until the end.
この調子で最後まで行てくれれりゃいいんだが
Their ace has both power and technique.
パワもテクニクもあるエス
They also have number sixteen,
who's an annoying decoy on top of his offensive prowess.
攻撃はもちろん囮としても極めて厄介な１６番
そして決まり始めた及川のサブ
And then there's Oikawa, who's starting to land his serves.
どこかを突き崩さなければこちらが崩される
If we can't counter those three, we're done for!
Both of us are talented.
互いに高い実力
The more we struggle for dominance,
the more fatal the consequences will be...
それは拮抗していればこそ
少しでもバランスを崩された方が
...when one of us loses our balance.
致命傷を負う
喰らいついていけ
Hang on and don't let go!
All right!
Aoba Jousai                      Karasuno
しゃぁあ
The last set is really close too.
ファイナルセトも接戦だな
でもまだ一回もリドは奪えてない
But neither team has taken a significant lead yet.
This is where they have to fight really hard to not fall ever further behind.
ここは離されないよう粘らないとな
Asahi! Get this one!
旭ここ一本
しゃあ
Yeah!
N—
Nice aim!
ナイスコス
There was no way you could've gotten that one.
今のは取れねぇわ
Just get the next one!
次次
Aoba Jousai                   Karasuno
Do it again, Asahi!
旭もう一本ナイサ
Yes!
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
Yeah!
よしゃ
Damn it...
またおいでなすたか
Here he comes again.
Give us a good one, Oikawa!
及川ナイサ
Olé!
Yes!
よしここで決めて及川のサブ切てくれ
Here's our chance! Tanaka!
チャンスチャンス田中
Now score here and stop Oikawa from serving!
よしゃ
Okay!
Watch the fast attack!
速攻来るよ
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
Finish it, Kyoutani!
京谷ラスト
Watch the right!
ライトライト
田中さん
Tanaka.
Shut down!
ドシャトォオオ
Yes!
Yes! They did it!
おしゃ切た
Nice block!
ナイスブロク
今ツキと田中のブロク入れ替わたな
Tsukki and Tanaka switched places just now.
Yeah.
ストレト来るて読んでたのか
Did they read that a straight spike was coming?
Great job, Tsukishima!
いいぞ月島
I knew it.
やぱり
Tanaka's been getting into it
with number sixteen, hasn't he?
田中あの１６番に絡んでましたよね
You mean like pick a fight with the guy?
喧嘩売てたてことか
Like in the second set,
２セト目でも１６番狙てブロクアウト獲たり
he kept trying to do a wipe off of number sixteen's block.
Or when there wasn't anyone blocking a cross-court spike, he hit a straight spike that barely got past number sixteen.
クロスにブロクいないのに
１６番のいる狭いストレト側をあえて抜いたりしてた
Seriously? I didn't notice!
マジか気付かなかた
It looks like number sixteen is fighting back
and hitting straight spikes to where Tanaka is.
１６番も対抗して
田中のいるストレト側に打てきてるみたいだたから
I think Tsukishima also figured that out.
月島もそれに気付いたんじゃないかと
You read him so well, Tsukishima!
よく読んだな月島
How'd you come up with that?
どうしたおい
It was nothing.
This is a chance to take the momentum.
流れを引き寄せるチャンスだ
Don't let it go to waste!
大事に行け
Got it!
オライ
Nice receive.
ナイスレシブ
Watch number sixteen!
１６番来るぞ
You need to get that point back yourself!
自分で取り返しな
It's going out!
アウト
All right!
よしゃあ
Yes! Finally!
よしゃ来た
All right! They turned it around!
Karasuno
Aoba Jousai
よしゃ逆転
Karasuno
Aoba Jousai
Keep it up!
このまま行け
Yeah!
行け
うまく煽れたんじゃないですか１６番
Looks like we pushed the right buttons for number sixteen.
Don't tell me Ryuu did that on purpose!
まさか龍は狙て煽たのか
No.
いや挑発はしてたのかもだけど
He may've been challenging him, but that wasn't his goal.
狙てはないな
That's just his nature.
あれは
そういう習性だ
そしてその習性を月島がうまく利用したて感じですかね
And I guess Tsukishima was able to take advantage of said nature.
盤石にみえた青城に綻びが見えた
Seijou seemed as solid as a rock,
but now we're starting to see some cracks.
This is our chance to bring them down!
ここが突き崩すチャンス
Let's keep the pressure on!
畳み掛けるぞ
Yeah!
おおす
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
H
a
S
e
i
c
k
y
o
n
u
d
S
e
!
a
s
o
n
あれ誰高校生
Who's that? A high school kid?
He said he just wants to practice with us.
練習だけさせてほしいんだと
I saw him with a different club on Saturday.
あいつ土曜に別のサクルでも見たな
If he's in high school, what about his school's team?
高校生なら部活は
He's probably the type that doesn't get along with the rest of the team.
要約すると部に溶け込めない系
Is he going through his rebellious stage?
反抗期
I'm surprised he's playing a team sport.
よくチムスポツやてんな
I'm sure he's playing because
there's something he likes about it.
何かしら魅力があるからやるんだべ
Oh, Kiyoshi.
清さんチス
Hi.
Otherwise, he wouldn't come
all the way out here to practice.
じゃなきゃこんなとこまで来て練習なんかしねぇ
日本日本日本
Japan! Japan! Japan! Japan!
ままあ常に人は足んないしいいんでない
W-Well, we're always short on people,
so it's probably fine.
Not to mention, he's better than us.
私達よりうまいし
What?!
はぁいや負けねぇし
I could take him!
Someone's mad.
ムキになてる
Shut up.
うるせぇ
Give us another good serve, Tsukishima!
月島もう一本ナイサ
オライ
Got it!
Mad Dog!
狂犬ちゃん
よしゃ
All right!
Aoba Jousai                  Karasuno
タイムアウト挟んでもダメか
The timeout didn't help, did it?
Maybe this is his limit.
もうムリなんじゃねぇ
Seijou's got plenty of players,
so why don't they switch him out?
青城は替えいるんだからそろそろ引込めてもいいんじゃねぇ
Switch gears!
切り替えもう一
Just focus—
Go scold him, Iwa!
岩ちゃん行け喝
You need to calm down if you
want to go back out on the court.
冷静になりなさい
またコトに出たいなら
Pull yourself together already.
ささと復活しろよもう後がないんだぞ
We've got our backs to the wall here.
Like I care. Shut up.
うるせぇ知るかよ
All right!
よしゃ
Yahaba, don't push him too much.
矢巾あんま責めてやんな
Sorry, but no.
すみません嫌です
You fell for our opponent's taunts,
got pissed off, and then self-destructed.
相手の挑発にまんまとノてアツくなて自滅
Talk about lame.
くそダサいな
What?
You had the nerve to come back,
and then you got to play right away.
お前がのこのこ戻てきてあさり試合なんか出たりしてさあ
Some guys have a problem with that.
それに不満がある奴もいるわけよ
Me, for example.
俺とかな
But...
問題起こしたワケでもないし
It's not like he caused any problems,
so I guess it doesn't matter as long as we can use him in matches.
試合で使えるなら別にいいんでない
Will he be able to keep up in practice?
ちゃんと練習ついてこられんのか
ブランクあんだろ
He'll have blanks to fill.
Communication is one of those.
コミュニケションも含めてだけどな
Well...
Those aren't the movements of someone who hasn't been practicing.
あれは練習してない奴の動きじゃないね
I thought it was pretty cold-hearted to both you and us.
冷たいと思たよ
オレたちにもお前にも
でもそんなことは問題じゃない
But that's not the problem.
レフト
Left!
The players we need in order to win are chosen as regulars.
勝ちに必要な人間がレギュラに選ばれる
ワンタチ
I touched it!
Someone cover it!
オライ
Got it!
And you were one of the chosen.
そしてお前が選ばれた
So do your job right.
だたら相応の仕事をしろ
矢巾噛み付かれんじゃねぇか大丈夫か
I think Yahaba's gonna get bitten.
Hope he's okay.
Go stop him.
お前止めてこいよ
No way!
Well, that's all just a facade.
ていうのはまあ建前だ
先輩の晴れ舞台に泥塗たら
If you ruin this for our upperclassmen,
絶対に許さねぇからな
I'll never forgive you!
お前もとチャラい奴だと思てた
I thought you were more shallow than that.
それで間違てねぇよ
You're not wrong there.
I may be shallow, but I respect our upperclassmen.
チャラくたて先輩は尊敬すんだよ
As long as you're on the court,
any point won or lost belongs to the team.
コトにいる以上得点も失点もチムのものだろ
頼むから力貸してくれよ
So come on.
Help us win.
オライ
Got it!
センタ
Center!
Kunimi!
国見ちゃん
Kunimi's attack might be...
国見の攻撃ある可能性
a tip!
フェイント
Ryuu!
龍
All right!
Aoba Jousai                Karasuno
Nice spike!
ナイスキ
I'm amazed you saw that coming, Kageyama.
影山よく読んだな
Thanks.
あざす
Huh? He's already back.
あれあいつもう戻てきた
He's going back in?
戻すのか早かたな
That was quick.
I'm sure it's a gamble for Seijou, though.
青城にとては賭けだろうけどな
All right!
よしゃ
Let it go!
アウトアウト
All right!
よしゃ
S-Shake it off...
ドドンマイ
Nagamushi Jr. High               South Third Jr. High
He's not doing well today.
あいつ今日調子悪いしどうする
What should we do?
We don't have any better attackers than him.
あいつより攻撃力あるやついないしなあ
But if his condition gets any worse, we're in for a boatload of trouble.
でもこれ以上調子崩したらめんどくさいぞ
Let's just see how things go.
とりあえずほかに回しつつ様子を見よう
Give us a good serve, Tanaka!
田中ナイサ
Okay.
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
狂犬ちゃん
Mad Dog!
及川ドＳだな
Oikawa's a total sadist.
They have absolute trust in each other, no questions asked.
問答無用で無慈悲な信頼だな
ここに来て結構経たな高校生一匹狼
It's been a while since you started coming here,
lone wolf high school kid.
お前青葉城西なんだてな強豪じゃねぇか
I heard you go to Aoba Jousai.
Aren't they pretty good?
I applied there but couldn't get in.
オレ昔落ちたんだよ
You're running away from your team
and practicing elsewhere without rest.
チムから逃げてあちこちで定住することなく練習
Sure are taking the easy way out, huh?
そりゃ楽な道を選んだもんだ
What?
チムつうのは頼もしく時に煩わしく
A team is reliable, annoying at times,
and powerful allies, yet they cause a lot of stress.
力強い味方であり重圧だ
You really think you're actually playing volleyball even though you can't face that head-on?
それと向き合うこともしないでバレやてるつもりかよ
自分がチムを向きチムも自分を向く
You need to face your team,
and your team needs to face you.
If you can do that, you may butt heads, but you'll both improve as a result.
それができたならチムも自分もぶつかりあて強くなれる
All right!
おおしゃああ
And if you ever manage that, just know that you're lucky.
そんでもしそれができたらラキだと覚えとけ
A team like that is hard to find.
そういうチムはどこにでもあるものじゃない
All right!
よしゃあ
いいチムじゃねぇか
Looks like a great team.
Yeah!
Make sure you face them head-on.
ちゃんと向き合えよ
Sorry! I'll get the next one!
すまん次は取る
Yeah!
Aoba Jousai                   Karasuno
Kyoutani, you're serving next.
京谷次サブ
That was a nice spike.
よく打た
Thanks.
もしあの１６番が烏野にいたとして
If number sixteen were on our team,
I wonder what I'd do in this situation.
今の場面自分だたらどうするかな
及川やぱりあいつすごくて怖いわ
Oikawa is amazing and terrifying at the same time.
All right, let's score here!
さあ一本取るぞ
Yeah!
With that play, it appears as though the oddball
number sixteen now fits in with the rest of the team.
今のプレでこれまで異物だた１６番が
青葉城西というチムに完全に溶け込んだように見えた
厄介だぜ
That can't be good.
We haven't lost
チムとしての力ならうちも負けてはいません
when it comes to our strength as a team.
This is just the start!
ここからです
Yeah.
Give us a good serve, Kyoutani!
京谷ナイサ
Ryuu!
龍
Yeah!
よしゃ
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
渡ちナイス
Nice one, Watacchi!
Watch the counterattack!
カウンタ
All right!
よしゃ
Damn it.
Aoba Jousai                  Karasuno
同点
They're tied!
青城追いついた
Seijou caught up!
京谷もう一本
Do it again, Kyoutani!
All right!
Here's our chance!
チャンスボル
Hit it, Asahi!
叩け旭
クソすいません
Damn it... Sorry!
All right!
You're awesome, Asahi!
旭さんさすがすふ飛ばしましたよ
You totally blew them away!
Thanks!
あざす
先輩はどちなのか
So who's the upperclassman here?
They can dig out Hinata's spike if they read
what he's going to do or force him to one side.
しかし日向のスパイク
コス絞られたり読まれたりすると拾われるな
Yeah.
I have to use Hinata better.
もと日向をうまく使てかねぇと
よしゃ
All right!
Karasuno                  Aoba Jousai
Ugh, again?
またか
及川のサブが回てくるたび寿命が縮んでる気がする
I feel like my lifespan gets shorter
every time Oikawa goes up to serve.
及川一本ナイサ
Give us another good serve, Oikawa!
及川さん頼みます
Oikawa, we're counting on you!
I feel like I'm going to throw up.
なんか吐きそうです
I'm sure we all do.
こち側は皆そうだろうな
We're almost at the end of the set.
そろそろ中盤も終わりここで大量失点は命取り
Giving up a lot of points right now would be fatal.
You have to stop him here!
一本で切れよ
Bring it!
さこい
Olé!
Daichi!
大地さん
I can't believe he got that.
あんなのよく拾うなあ
We have a chance here!
チャンスボル
Damn it!
Watch for the fast attack!
速攻来るぞ
金田一
Kindaichi!
ドンマイ
It's fine.
要求があるときは言う
If you have a request, say it!
及川さんは言えば改善してくれるし
Oikawa improves things if I say something, but if I hesitate, nothing gets across to him!
遠慮してたら伝わらない
あの及川さん
Hey, Oikawa.
That one is a bit hard to sync up with, or, like...
今のだとちょと合わせづらいというかなんというか
Hm...
分かた
Got it.
でもまだ変えずに行てみよう
But try again without changing anything.
Again!
お前の打点は
For you, the point of impact...
後ボル一個分先だ
needs to be about a ball's length closer!
Yes!
That was a really sharp broad jump.
キレのあるブロド
Kindaichi's movements have changed since the interhigh.
金田一の動きがインハイ予選のときと違う
Shake it off! We'll stop them here!
ドンマイここ切るよ
一本集中
Concentrate on getting one point!
Karasuno                Aoba Jousai
ブレイク
Two in a row!
Seijou's turning it around in the second half of the set!
後半に来て青城逆転した
まさにチムとチムの総力戦になてきやがた
It's now an all-out war between the teams.
Indeed.
そして青葉城西というチム全体の底上げをするのが
The person who brings up the Aoba Jousai team as a whole
is Oikawa, right?
及川くんというわけですね
及川さんもう一本ナイサア
Give us another good one, Oikawa!
Yeah, I know, sir.
分かてるよ先生
うちのチムの総力はこんなもんじゃねぇよ
But this isn't even close to the total strength of our team!
さこい
Bring it!
Come on!
上げろ
Give us another good serve, Oikawa!
及川さんもう一本ナイサア
Olé!
すまん月島頼む
Sorry!
Get it, Tsukishima!
押し込め金田一
Push it over, Kindaichi!
All right!
サンキュ月島
Thanks, Tsukishima!
月島次サブ
Tsukishima, you're serving next!
Go wild out there, Shouyou!
暴れて来い翔陽
Right!
We'll stop them at one point!
一本で切るぞ
Yeah!
The Great King really is amazing.
大王様てやぱすげぇな
Do you truly understand that?
わかんのか
I can tell there's something amazing about him.
なんかすげぇのは分かる
だがしかし
However!
As long as I'm around, you're invincible!
俺がいればお前は最強だ
かけぇなおい
That was cool, you know?
またくだよ
Seriously...
They keep digging out your spikes, so I don't know what you mean.
拾われまくりが何言てやがる
What'd you say?!
なんだと
Baseless courage is good!
根拠のない自信いいね
M-My courage isn't baseless!
あありますよ根拠
よしゃ
All right!
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
Mad Dog!
狂犬ちゃん
ナイスワンチィィィ
Nice contact!
オライ
Got it!
俺に持て来ォォォォいやぁぁぁ
Give it to me!
I jumped too far forward!
前に飛びすぎたネト近ぇ
The net's really close!
トスがネトに近すぎないか
Isn't the set a bit close to the net?!
It's basically right on top of it!
ほぼネトの真上だぞ
No one's there!
誰もいねぇ
Slam it down!
打ち下ろせ
前だ
Up front!
いよいよファイナルセト１７対１６
It's finally the third set, and the score is 17-16.
It's the final stretch.
大詰めだな
Yeah.
ぜてぇ勝つぞ
We're definitely gonna win.
Yeah.
全部オレに持て来い
Give all the sets to me!
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回ハイキュ極限スイチ
"The Absolute Limit Switch."
Episode Twenty-four:
The Absolute Limit Switch
Don't just ignore me!
そこスルすんなよ